Explorer is her middle name.
Dora and the Lost City of Gold is a family, comedy,
adventure film directed by James Bobin.
Dora, a girl who has spent most of her life exploring the jungle with her parents,
now must navigate her most dangerous adventure yet: high school.
Always the explorer, Dora quickly finds herself leading Boots (her best friend, a monkey), Diego, and a rag tag group of
teens on an adventure to save her parents and solve the impossible mystery behind a lost Inca civilization.
Dora, played by Isabela Merced.
Diego, played by Jeffrey Wahlberg.
Sammy, played by Madeleine Madden.
Alejandro Gutierrez, played by Eugenio Derbez.
Cole - Dora's Father, played by Michael Peña.
Elena, played by Eva Longoria.
Dora and the Lost City of Gold is a 2019 American adventure comedy film directed by
James Bobin and written by Nicholas Stoller and Matthew Robinson.
Loosely based on the animated television series, it is the first
feature film in the Dora the Explorer franchise.
It stars Isabela Moner, Eugenio Derbez, Michael Peña and Eva
Longoria, with Danny Trejo as the voice of Boots.
The "Lost City of Gold" is based on the legendary Inca city, Paititi.
A live-action Dora film was announced in 2017, and Moner
was cast in the title role in May 2018.
Filming took place from August to December 2018 in Australia and Peru.
John Debney and Germaine Franco composed the film's score.
The film was theatrically released in the United States
on August 9, 2019, by Paramount Pictures.
It received generally positive reviews from critics, and was a moderate box office
success, grossing $121 million against a budget of $49 million.
A reboot, Dora and the Search for Sol Dorado, was released in 2025.
The film explores themes of peru, museum, fox, based on cartoon, jungle.
The tone is lighthearted.